SUMIT **MUKHIJA**

Apt 8, Georges place, Dun Laoghaire, Dublin · (+353)-894843884

sumukhija@gmail.com · http://sumit.cc · github.com/sumitmukhija

An experienced Software Developer dedicated to creating and optimizing interactive, user-friendly, and feature-rich software applications. Leverage analytical skills and strong attention to detail to deliver efficient solutions.

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2020

MASTER'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF DUBLIN

Modules include Advanced software engineering, Machine learning, Data analytics, text analytics. Working towards a dissertation on creating a domain specific language to create better graphs with **Haskell**.

MAY 2015

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, RAJIV GANDHI PROUDYOGIKI VISHWAVIDYALYA

Modules included Data structures, Object oriented programming, Operating systems, Database management system, Web technologies. The Project involved a Java application that could split files in to parts depending on the space left on the USB drive. Also volunteered with the training and placement cell.

SKILLS

- Python
- Flask
- SQL
- Object Oriented Programming
- Test driven development
- Agile

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript (ES6)
- ReactJS
- Continuous Integration
- Git version control
- Docker

EXPERIENCE

JULY 2016 – MARCH 2019 SOFTWARE ENGINEER, **SMARTSERV INC.**

 Created a Python library for queuing jobs and processing them in the background with workers.

- Joined the team assigned to redesign and revamp the product using React.
 Componentize the ticketing & time-card module for a cleaner maintainability.
- Delivered Gravity payment gateway integration.
- Created dashboards for monitoring the usage pattern of the application and eventually to detect customers at risk.
- Revamped the invoicing module.
- Delivered updates and fixes for critical application modules including invoicing, timecards, activity status, inventory, and ticket creation.

AUGUST 2015 – JULY 2016 ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, **APOSTEK SOFTWARE LLP.**

- Developed and published three mini-games, in an application called Slot Machine for periodic releases for iPhone and iPad. Also worked with Alphonso Ad integration, bug fixes.
- Worked with the Care.com team on features like insurance, pet-care and adult-care, Google Maps integration. The Care.com was once in top trending applications in the US store.

CERTIFICATION(S)

Oracle Certified Java Programmer (2015-2018) Scored 100%

SIDE PROJECTS

EPILOGUE — Book recommendation system

An application that interacts with a Python Flask backend. The Flask server uses a Kaggle dataset, named Goodbooks that consists of information on 10,000 books. Moreover, additional information was procured using Google Books API and OpenLibrary API. The recommendations are generated based on genre, author and description.

BAGGAGE CAROUSEL — Custom Object detection

An application that uses Tensorflow to detect a particular bag on the airport carousel. The agenda is to provide the user with an audio and haptic feedback when the target bag is detected on the carousel. The model used was Mobilenet v1.

SEQUENTIAL TICKET NUMBER GENERATOR

A Redis based solution to a very common problem of generating unique sequential ids. The solution was employed to generate unique ticket numbers in the CRM product.

BLOGS

Medium: @sumukhija

Contributions in - TowardsDataScience

Hackernoon